{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There are seven boxes numbered from 1 to 7 and 30 identical balls. In how many ways can these 30 balls be distributed among these seven boxes such that each box contains at least one ball and no two boxes contain the same number of balls?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"10080","CORRECT_ANSWER":"10080","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Ours is a big family and I have thrice as many brothers as sisters, while my sister, Bharathi, has four times as many brothers as sisters. How many children do my parents have?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"21","CORRECT_ANSWER":"21","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rani and Lakshmi can type ten identical books in 25 and 20 days respectively. If Rani, Lakshmi and Veena, together, undertake the work of typing the ten books for a sum of Rs.6000, and complete the work in ten days, find Veena\u2019s share (in Rs.).\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"600","CORRECT_ANSWER":"600","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the value of   <img Width='116' Height= '79' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAHMAAABPCAYAAADY+\/owAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAaiSURBVHhe7Z1tTFNXGMcRBxK\/OHXRqcAXljCJRGFfhoiKiDinoFOiC+pkcSDOV9TZusoQivFlETLDouILwiAiIjiDEKUk4HQULDCRieALyEBnDKjAwIg+6zk+FrQtLQbae889v+SJ93\/OxWh\/3HPPfa0NSARVQQHs2bMXE5tIQmZDQwM4OTmCn99sbGET5mXGKWPBzs4OHBwcYLb\/HGxlE6ZldnV1wbRp3nDmTBZ8G7oKPD0\/wx42YVrmy5cvcQlgxfLl4DHFExObSGYCtDwkBDw8uEwm4DIZgstkiOAlS2DiRDdMbCIZmVsiIyEwMAgTm0hGJpnZ9p7dsohkZEoBLpMhuEyGsKmtrYXU1FRISUnhJeJKT08Hm+LiYggLC4PVq1fzEnGtW7eOD7MswWUaICMjA\/bsFd+FbC7zHS5dvAg2NjYw03cWtogHLhN58eIFbNywAWxtbWH48OHw1eLF2CMeuEyktbUFfHymgUpVCAuDAsF3Ft8yRUvvU31fzA3gMlmBy2QILpMhmJJZV1cHr169wiQ9fGfOgM+9vDCJBz2ZmzdthLFjP2b+2l9fhId9B6tCQzGJB53MJ0+eQHh4GD1gdnH5RNJbpljRyZwxfTq4urpCcHAwODo6mZRZdf063L17FxNHCOhkFhYWQrd2aD148BcYMeJDkzIj1qyBAwfiMXGEgN4+U6mMhZEjR5mUuUMmgxMnkjFxhICezLg4pVGZlRUVkJSURMvf3x9CQkJ0ubKyEtfqobOzEzQaDZSVlfEaxLp\/\/z79vPslU3PtGiQmJtLy0x6HLV26TJc1mnJcq4eOjg5Qq9VQUlLCaxDrzp079PPul8ze7JDLITn5JCaOENCTqVD8qD08sTUpc014OJ8AaVEoFHD6dCYm66Ins7q6GrKyzmIyTkV5OT1TJGXIKEaOy2NiYrHFuujJ5Jjm4YMH4OvrC\/Z29jBs2DDYv\/9n7LEuXOZ7UFLyJ8z\/cj7Uakem8ePH8S2TFUaPGsVlssJHo0dzmazAZTKEpGXm5OTAs2fPMIkfB+1sVqHYicm6WFSmXC6jx2W3b78+\/cQCs7SHKEeOJGGyLhaR2djYCF8vW0ZF2tnbQ319A\/ZwBhKLyPx+bQRMmeIBCQkJVOa9e\/ewxzDkSsv58+cxcczFIjKbm5vpn2Wlarp1mpL5a2IirFz5DSaOuVh0n1lw6fVDOaZkZpw6BZGRWzBxzMWiMlUFl4zKrKmpAZlMRmvevHng6empy2np6bhWD93d3VBUVAT5+fmSLZVKRa8Zv0EwMh8\/fkzvQyL1w7ZtEBS0UJdv3LiBa\/VAbgUl75ElN5WJpci\/l\/zfDfW9T9XX18Pz58\/xExHoMPtbaiqsX78BE8dcBCnz2NGjEBGxFhMbkJFnqpcXqEtLsWXgsajM9rY2qKqqemtoMERLSws0Nb2eAbMA+eX91NWV\/iJfvvwHtg48FpUpRXJysukF7MmTJ9PXi3OZIuZsVhYcO3acHmsPGTIEioqLsWfg4TItxO26OjrMcpkMUFdby2WyApfJEFxmP8nOzqZnRoRIzc2bVGaBSoUtAw8zMlNOnqQfFvlCGiHy78OHEBoaCjW3bmHLwCN6ma2trbB50yYqklTuhQvYIz1EL5Oc+nN2doa0tDSwt7fTHqSfwx7D\/NPYCEe1P8MiopdJTv2R9951dXbSLdOUzFK1Gnx8fDCxBTP7zOamJrNkkoP3RYsWYWILZmQ+aG42KrNVu\/Vu374dtm7dCitXrAAXFxe6TGrfvv241tuQJ5Lz8vIEW4au8UpCJvnqxatXr8KVK1fgxPHj4O3tTZdJlZfrP\/FNePToEb2rUKhFLqm9C3Mys7NzsMUwf1dXw4IFCzCxBVMyyYt\/z537HVsMU67RQGBgICa2YEZmt3ZGS57kbm9vxxbDkCH3za2f\/aGtrY3OnIUMMzIHE3IHnJubG+yM+glbhAmXaQJyC6i7+yS6P1Yq47BVmHCZfUAmSx8MHQrztROmsWPGQJSJLZPcy0tebkVOYlgDLrMPyCFAbm4uXXZ2cgKZTE6XjUEeVfSe6m21fSuXaSbjx40DuXwHJuPM8Z9jtXf1cplm0pfM\/Lw8yMzMpF+Q5z7JHZKTk2km71Pq6PgP1xp8uEwzMSaTvMns8KFDsHv3boiOjqanCqOiomgmpwqfPrXcU+JcppmYO8zODZiLS5aHyzQTxwkTIDZWick45shMiI8HPz8\/TORnAiB6VwxdrqiooH2VlX\/RHLMrGgJ6\/Z2kLz4+AVNvAP4HP4UUF5egZx0AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  .\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='37' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACUAAAAiCAYAAADYmxC7AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANzSURBVFhH7ZdLLJxRFMdHxCPGggbV2FKJ2nQmKY3Uo5RRjzakwarKyJRJJWYSpkFIbGhEWFhIhC5kphtdEGvVkKFshAVBFx7xiKKeU8S\/955eROahfF\/Uor\/kJPece79v\/nO\/e8+5V4FLmJ+fh16vd2lbW1titDxcKspsNsNkMqG\/v9+hDQ4OipHycakog8GA8fFx4d0MLkWdnJxAq9VidXVVRG4Gl6LW1tZQWFhI4m4Sl6KsViuMRiO1bTYbioq0SEpKQmxs7JmNjHyjfjkwGg0oLi52LaqzsxPNzc3U\/j43B4VCgfSMDJSXl5\/Z9PQ09UuloqKc3p\/54qVrUTU1Nejr66P25+5ueshm+0W+XPCUo1apoFT6IiAgANnZr1yL0ul0mJ2dpXZ1VRU92FBfj7y8PNTW1rL89JP6pDA6Oor8\/HwsLS3haUI8kpM1zkXt7e2hoKCA1hInIT6eZiomJgZZWVlwd3fHg8hIrKysUL8cREc9QkpK6kVRPFEODQ1Re2pqCiUlJdTmtLW1oaWlRXjA5OQEiTSZ3ovIOXy3Hh8fOzVnPI6Ouiiqvb0dHh4eiIiIIL+npwd1dXXUdsbdoEA2a9nCO2diYoJm2ZG9Ky2lr+AIO1HLy8vo7e2lfz\/HdhoX2dXVRX38JXFxcWho+ED+Kd7eXnid\/0Z45xwdHWF7e9uh7ezsOM17dqJOCQ4Opn\/EZ2lsbIxifMpVqockeGDgKxYXF6Fnn5b7wyMjNEYO1Ow3EhIS7UU1NjbCzc2N7YJk7O7uiijL7qzUxLFk6enpCV9fXwQGBcFssYheeUh7norc3Dx7UZubmzQDarVaRC7CUwQv0AcHByIiH\/v7+2R2ojjV1dVobW0V3s3jUNS\/5naK4muDp4PbZApecPlO40eS22Bci4InssPDw1tl\/xf63yKbKH7dampqQkdHB1YkXjQki+LFNzcnh6pAeHg4K0FK+Pn5UY28LpJFfezsIEEWyyfyNzY2EBYairD74eRfB8mivrDPVllZJbw\/FLFrmaeXt\/CujuwLnR+fAwMDkKJJFZGrI7uo9LQ0+PgosbCwKCJXRzZRP9bX2ckxGv7+d2AdHhbR6yGLqNmZGdxjJ9bQsDB2j1sQ0esjWRQ\/kYaEhCAx6ZmISEeyKENZGaWEJ+yonMmu9BqNhkyneytGXBXgN8AY9SGSFgYwAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='36' Height= '33' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACMAAAAhCAYAAABTERJSAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANdSURBVFhH7ZdNLFxRFMcnWPiKhOlSaGLQRDTtoEEXxrRIpqNNVRcWbYlREx+JEguVIlGD0EUNTXwGsWhrw66mCxKJSKaRILGwEIMKEWPUoDMx\/n3vupMxmY\/meQ9d9Jec5J5zT977vzvn3nNHhL\/Q2tqK0tJSt1ZeXo6joyOayR+vYqxWK\/Ly8jA5OenWZmZmaKYweBWj0+nQ2NhIvcvHqxitVovh4WHqXT5exVRXV2N2dpZ6wNHhIXZ3jdQTFrPZ7F1MUVERtre3ybiu7h1CQkIQHByM5ORkLCwukrgQqItfIyfnmWcxrAiVSkXGLc0aiEQitLW1Y2pqCrfj4xEREYnj499k\/qJYrRa8qaggz85+\/MSzmOnpadTU1JDxp64uvK2tJWOW77oJ8gCDYY1GuGM+OIBEEkU+SiKRQKnM9ixmaGgInZ2d1Dtjf98EvV6PjIyHSJPJYLFY6Qx3zOYDdDEfyZ5TykcKpKfLPYupr68nW\/s8rS0tCAsLI6vS3z9Ao\/xJl6VBLn\/gEDMyMoK4uDgsLS0Rv7i4GGtrzj+D0WgktaRpaiKCvk1M0BkHKysrGB0ddWvLy8s0yxl5uswh5vT0FA0NDfD390dJSQlJKCgoIHGWnZ0dmEwmMrYTFBiIFy9fUc\/B\/Pw8aSHuTK\/\/QbOccRJjp5Yp0qCgIFIX7BljR5aWhqSke9QDfm5skJVp0jTTCD\/cijEYDPD19UVWVhYGBhw18fXLZ\/JyNl5VVQWxOAyRkTfJigmB9O4dSKUJrgWsVCrJi8+fvCw6pj4UCgVSUlJQVlaOra2zw1AIerq70dPT4ypmbGwMoaGh2Nvbo5Grw0WMzWbD+vo69a4WFzHXyb8lZnx8HGq1+tqNPd9Ec3NzGBwcvHZje+H\/mvGEIGLYBso2WPut8KLwEsM20srKSgQEBCCQaZx+fn7M\/6kynJzYaAY3eInp6+0lraO9\/QO5Omi1HcT\/2NFBM7jBS0wv00\/y8\/Opd0Z0VBSeMpfriyBoAZuYfubr44P3TRoa4YZgYiwWCxKkUsTG3mLuyr9olBuCiGF3U1JiIqJjYrC6aqBR7vAWs7CwgPDwcKSm3r\/witjhJWZzcxM3xGLk5j6nEX7wEqMqLCRbOTMzk9wC2Wspa319\/TSDC8AfI4FrrB9m4rIAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='37' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACUAAAAiCAYAAADYmxC7AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAO3SURBVFhH7ZhPLNthGMc721zEEraJsPbgZDu4UFa2ka062VjCzC7YZgk2EZGw+TMy1y3hIGILYZlktsOQ0I06IGJxEIIDDkKMukwNxfyp797nzaub\/dpfRxtz2Cd5kvd5fk\/b7+993r9VwAGTk5PIysqyazk5OVhfXxfZrsGhqLq6OpSWlqKrq8um9ff3i0zX4VBUdnY2xsfHhXc4yIra3t5GWloaFhcXReRwkBU1MzOD9PR04R0esqK6u7tRUFAgPOBNfT2CgoKgUqlw6fJlGAyd4olryM\/LQ0ZGpryo6upq1NbW8vbrV6+gUChw\/\/4D1DNxERHh3O\/t7eXPnaWosJB\/X1zcLXlR1Es9PT28HRaqZkIu8TZh2bbAze0YMh89FhHb7Ozs8LFpj7m5OajVIfDw8MDZM2cQn3Dbvij6MhpP9CFifn4eC6YF3ibM5hUcY2+Wl\/9ERGzTaTAgMTFReFKGhoaQmnoPs7Oz0F67Cq022r6opaUlPvPsveWjzAwcP3ECExMTImKbpo8fERwcLDx5wjUXER2t2yuqsrISzc3NvD0wMIDc3Fze\/pPi4iJe\/\/fvP4jIXnZLRkaiNBqN1bdYLCJLSkS4Zq+ompoaXleaWURjYyMqKip4e5cfP9ZxOyGBC2pr04uolC99fbyXybRaLXx8fKz+s5ISkSVFIspoNPIlgH5wdHQUVVVVaGlpEU+BtbU1REVFwc\/PH2Nj8iv85uYmlpeXuTW+e4ewsDCrbzabRZYUiahdAgICEB8fz0pUbN1eqBwpyclc8Nu3DRgeHkYf6w2y6elpnmOPlqYmNrvUwpNHHRKMyMgoqShal+jHqdu3trZ4zMRmnUqlhK+vL+spP3h5eVnt+fMynmOPz58+ITY2VnjyxMXeRFLSXamo1dVVLopKtQsNTur6lZUVPit\/N0fHFnoxKv3fQHlkElEE9VZra6vwDh+bov41R1MUjQnaQo6SKfR6PXQ6HZ9tR8FIi4LWIFrsjpL9H+h\/i8tEdbS3o7y8HA0NDeyi8V1ED4bTomgFvnnjBt8FAgMD4e5+En7+\/hgeGREZ+8dpUS9fvOCCOjoM3Dca53Da2xtX2MZ6UJwWpW9rQ1nZ3k35ui4a55RK4e0flw\/0hW\/fWAnd2YHuoYjsH5eK2tjYYLeeUH4QNJkOfqt2maiv7DZ94cJ5KJUqhydTR7hE1NDgIE55erJbSwi7hplE9OA4LWp6agre7AR6JylJRJzHaVH3UlOsx2c69sbExHB78vTXfxD7A\/gJfwzr+rQZG2YAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='38' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACYAAAAjCAYAAAD48HgdAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAPgSURBVFhH7ZdbSJRBGIZXvNC8EivRsgu9KEQvvOqk0MGsbgxKjRLykJB4qLwpJU3FDW0TERSzo6umkqFpbivYhmiQK0olmIVemefygHhEd\/Xtn69pQ9f\/39bdTKIHPpj3m9nZd2dm5yCDCYaHhxEXFycZfX19vLX1MGmspqYGCQkJaGxsXDOampp4S+ti0lhiYiK0Wi1XG4dJY1FRURgaGuJq45A0Njk5icjISOh0Op7ZOCSNtbW10fpiLC8tIfnGDQQHByMwMNAQ5RUVVG8tgoKCoFK9lDZWVFSEvLw8Kk+Mj0Mmk2HnTjf4+fkZ4tHjIqq3FL0wK+FhYfQdZeXl0sZSU1OhVquprG1poQ+9e\/eetDnMzc1hYWGBK2PeNDdhz+7dsLOzh42NDZ5WVkobi46ORk9PD5Xz8\/Nga2uLhoYGKJVKaDQayv8O169dw5OyMq6MuZmSgvDwcHR2dpKxsvIKcWMzMzOIiIgw\/NKzIcE0Yq6urnB3d6fy\/v0H8PXbN6qXIvrSJdx\/8IArcUaFvn5M5Spjzc3Nhq2hq6sLsbGxVGbcu1dIemBggHTL27fUyblzoaSluHrlCkpKS7kSp184QYyMZWZmUpJNH6OqqopyUpw8cRxbt23naiVyuZz6YuHl5YVDhw8bdKmIyTWN1dXV0YccHBywJGwN2dnZqK6upjqdbhG5ubl4\/ryG9E+O+fvDxXUHVythI9\/b20sRduECFHfuGPTY2BhvtZI1jTEGBwepgplMT0+nxchgG+z2bVuxRTA9OjpKudbWVmobGxdPWorL8fFQFhdzJY6oMYavry+8vb0RExOD6elpnhWMCOelk5MT7O23wMfHhzo4KLSdmJjgLcSJungRdwsLuRLnizCarF9lcYmxsdraWqoMCQnhmV+MjIygoKCA9rfKZ8+g1y\/xGmnYH6m\/v58rcebn51FfXy\/M3JCxMbY9ODo6IikpiWf+DkbGGN3d3aILdKNY09hmYPMaa29vR4pwViUnJ2+ayMjIgKyjowMKhQJZWVmbJnJycv6vMbP5t40tLy\/j0cOHOCW8AQICAnD7tgJTU7+Os\/VgsTFm6qxwfLFjjD1U2OWSlffu3YfZ2VneynwsNtbx4QMZkctv8QxQItwkWE6trucZ87HYGLtdqFSqFbeMz58\/kbHqVfc3c\/gjiz\/ozGm6u42Pm74SiWF1Y2lpqTRaGs1rnlkfVjO2uLiI0NDzZOqVGU87MaxijD1o\/XwPwsXFBR8\/dvGsZVhsjD1cjh45Aje3XcIN9yvl9Ho9BdtK1ovFxupevKDpc3Z2hqenJzw8PAyh1bbyVuYCfAfq2eDOHmz0rAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Three circles A, B and C, all of equal radius, are drawn - each touching the other two externally. If another circle is now drawn through the three points of contact (where the circles touch each other), what is the ratio of the area of this circle to that of the circle passing through the centres of the three original circles?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 : 9\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9 : 16\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">For an odd positive integer <i>n<\/i>, satisfying 51&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&le;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;<\/span>&le;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;99, the quantity <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">3<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;<\/span>&minus;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&nbsp;<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> is always divisible by<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>48.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>24.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>18.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of these\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There are <i>n<\/i> numbers arranged in a row such that the product of the first <i>i<\/i> numbers among them is   <img Width='25' Height= '30' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABgAAAAeCAYAAAA2Lt7lAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHUSURBVEhL7Za9SwJhHMdvEXSovUCy0XKpy4auEJzSjDId1N4oAzepqaD6C2qtPSPrHyjbjDPKXtdeINGKGgrEFhe9b3r8UA+x5y5q8wMP3Od5Dj7Hc3fccdBIJLKDjY1NMjaaAicncbS2tMDlGqUZNqoC2WwWC8EgOI6DwWCAw+GkFTaqAre3N+B5HqKYwJAgQBAGaYWNqoAkSXQEWPv4vw\/U0gww6eN7MTAgkLHRHOjuMqOnp5eMjebA5eUFrq6uydhoDmilGWDCRaNReL3efxmBQABcKpVCPB7\/lyGKYvMms6kElpYWMTzsIPs9Pp8PsdgxWU1ge2sLy8srZNqRpCJmZ2fkz2pkd5dmVW6RVCwin8+T1XN+dgaLxQKdTicH9g8OaKUmEJyfg9XaT6bkOZOB3+8nq2d9bbX0zE8imUzKgb29KK3UBFwjTrS1tZMpST09wW63kzWmfCENAxPucZhMnWRK3t\/e4HSyf1UeHx7UB+7v7xAKheRRfuWNRmPFw+EwcrkcnVlFU6B8U9PptDxOEwnYbLaKZ0pbUSgU6MwqPwbc42Po6DCRKXl9eSn9zbHfkR8DM9NTMJu7yJR8lbbD4\/GQNebz4wN6vR6Hh0c0A3wDX\/BB1nZIPkYAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>   (for all values of <i>i<\/i>) and the product of the last <i>i<\/i> numbers among them is   <img Width='36' Height= '30' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACQAAAAeCAYAAABE4bxTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAO1SURBVFhH7ZdJTFNBHMbLYkRDlfbiRqICXpQLF40kGI2YuBxUhJtgoiGytm4JUNwQLVpADyIKUlQiBrfiAUg4IBpJQFNTSDDIBQvIYgiJsocGPmem\/\/bZ8GpdqiHRXzJpv2\/mzfvaN28WBbxAWloa8vIuk\/o5jMYylJUZSQFeCaTX63H37j1SP05T0ysolUqkpKaSQ4FmZ2cxOTkpjOHhYXR2djr17zA9PQ2bzUZK4tOnQSQnJUGhUIhyNCmZaijQ2NgY1q0LQ2xsLNRqNfz8\/LBy5So8fvxENPJEZORmJCQcIiWRlZmJ3NxcUhK3S0tF\/6bqaixftszlWnugkRGRNDBQifr6elgsFoSGhiBIpcbU1JRo+D1WrFiO6OgdpCSOHD4MjUZLSmKE3W9mZkZ8V6tUiI9PEN859kCjoyLQ5SsGYXIKC\/KF19fXT4571qxZjd2795CS0KSnIytLR2ousyzUdwOVlN4WJqewoEB4VqsV58+dE2+SXGlta0P4hvXOQOVGo7MuPDwcERERTn2\/slK0ceAx0I3im8Lk5BsMwvv4sQ8dHR1oYzeWK5+\/fEFYWKgzUDf7AY66uLg4MT4cure3V7Rx8EuB+vsHyHGPu0eWmpKCjIxMUnNxG2iUBnXh1WvC5FzIyXH+Q55QqYIQFbWFlET8wYNITk4hNRceyIfdY\/\/+GHIokI3NFxUVFXjP5h8H79rbhTcxMUGOe0wmExoaGkhJtDQ3w2w2k5oLn\/+qqqrYBNlEDgWaT\/wP5In5F6impgbpbEadD0Wr1ULR0tKCoqKieVGKi4v\/jyGP\/NuBtBoNKisfkJLnrwXK1unE2piTc4EceTwG4uvNwMCA+Ozp6UFjYyO6PnygWlf4fnx8fJyUHb6Wbdq0UYTx8fGBwZBPNfJ4DMRvEBKylu2bI9mqrsLiRYtE5zpdNrWQ2Ld3L8rv3CFl58zpbLG9bWYLrZ+vLy7p86hGnh8KtHTJEixcGIAXL19iaGiIbRf2iVBWaze1shO9fTtulZSQsmObtp86RmnP5ZVAC\/z9XY4qdbU1ovPXr9+QY2fXzp0wlpeTcmVwcNC7gU6cPEUO8KzaJDq3WFpRwA4DiYmJogQHB7ONWpRT19bW0RV\/IJD22HFygGrTU9G52fxWDGQ+6HnZtnUr8tnhwKH5Y3Lg1UD+7OCo0R4jxzXQt\/BHVsZOHXI4Al28pCdHHo+BOMrAQJw+c5YU0Pi8AQEBAejqcn39D8TE4OGjR6Rc4Udqfs31ohvkyAF8BfhI2837k44qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>   (for all values of <i>i<\/i>). If exactly three of the<i> <\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i>numbers are greater than   <img Width='19' Height= '28' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAAbCAYAAACeA7ShAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANVSURBVEhL5ZVLTBNRFIYL8kZAwyMBdAMtllKMWnAFKgkKGyKYKBAfmOAOFZWIVaEBE7WUBGolGgsUEzVaWFWLr8THQhfIY0MstIZGESQS1A0gIPB7e+bOSFU2ujHxSyZzHjP\/nHvv3HNlWAatVosnT59yDxgZeY+ysjLpcrne8MwPfivW0twMmUyGGzdv8QiwOT0diYlyNDQ0oKAgH8nJKkxNT\/OswC9iz58\/g6+PDwIDA3Hl6lWKXW+zkLjL5SLfQ3RUFI4cLeeegJfYp4kJhIaGorHRiISEBFZFI8XrDXXwYR9YyvpUNbZuy+KegJfYlsxM7N5TSHZUZCRMpstk9\/f3U2Vlhw\/j7bt3aDabyd+5M5\/yIpJYnV4PP39\/vH7twPDwMCIiIlBdrcP4+DjlLZZWBAcHU+VpaenQaDZh+\/YdlBORxNI0GoSEhCCSVRQeHk7DCgoKQlFxMRYWFuiZqakpOBwOslNSVCgsKiZbRBIbHR3F0NAQnE4nBgcGEB4Wxn6P0xR3OgcRExPDfpVn9Oyd27dpmJ33H5Av4jVnSwllVRqNl8ienZ1Fbs4OElDI5XQvLT1EuaX8XmxxET09PRgbG+MBAbvdjqamJrx4+ZJHvFm2sj\/hHxZzu93o6OiA1Wr9q8tms0HW3d2N+vp6GAyGv7qMRuN\/swD8Tni2Tl5eHuLj45Gamop2tjAifb29yMzIQFxcHHJycuFZuJ+RxGZmZpCiSqZuarFYsKuggLZNb18f5ue\/UTPcsGEjzNfMSFIokMi21fRynbaj3Uove\/ahiE6ng4NtejH3kbcjt3uI\/IePHpMvIomVHz2CNWvWoq5OD7VajezsbAwMDFKu4sRxxMbGke1hbm4Owaw91dTU8oiAJFZy4AB9TalUQs8aZVZWFnx9V7B5\/ICDJSVQKJL4k2xKvn4lsfLyYzwiIInt37cXfn7++Pz5C48Aq1etwoWLeuiqqyCXK3iUV8a6bkXFSR4RkMTOnjkD\/4AA7gko161DZeUptLY0s3a9kkeByclJVrUv2tqu84iAJPaqq4uGWVN7jr7cab9Hvu3uPTbUEbLPX7hIQlrtKfI9h8tSJDEPZvM1as8qlQrR0dGoYgeKyGWTic4GOfslPOeEtb2dZ0SA71JWgfjs2+cXAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  , what is the value of <i>n<\/i>?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>In a class of 100 students, the number of students who do not play Football is 12 more than those who do not play Volleyball. If the number of students who play neither of the games is eight less than those who play both, then find the number of students who play Volleyball.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"60","CORRECT_ANSWER":"60","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A thin wire which is 80 cm long is cut into three pieces along its length. The longest piece is three times as long as the middle sized piece and the shortest piece is 46 cm shorter than the longest piece. Find the length (in cm) of the shortest piece.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"8","CORRECT_ANSWER":"8","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If <em>a<\/em>, <em>b<\/em> <img height=\"7\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAYAAAAHCAYAAAArkDztAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAACMSURBVBhXVY0xCoQwAATzrHzDyiJNwNZHCMEHmNKvWEawS28jQQJiYZEmKBYjJ8fBLcw2A7uCb7ZtYxxHpmlinmd+om1b6rp+6fseEWPEGMMwDKSUOI6D8zwR3nuklCilKMuSoihomgbhnKOqKtZ1JYTAsizs+474VNd179R1XeScue\/7\/1xr\/WKt5QExjIT9RJ2zNgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"6\" \/> R, then the value of the expression <em>a<\/em><sup>2<\/sup><sup> <\/sup>+ 2<em>b<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> &minus; 6<em>a<\/em> &minus; 8<em>b<\/em> &minus; 3 lies in the interval <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>[18,  <img Width='14' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA4AAAAMCAYAAABSgIzaAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAFESURBVChTlZHPqoJAFMZ9BWnlgygErl25aFnrIDIQhBZB0qJo07qnEKQW7tq00RcQ3Bm4CF\/AAiv1u5xzncLLhcv9wTAzZ74z55\/UNA0EdK7rGs\/nE1VV8VnYhY7shCQe\/4vU7ng8HhxJRHy9XrxEZIpYliXbiI4jiUhAj7fbjYUitZ9I4oF+JeffiOMYjuNgs9kgz3O2vR3F7vs+RqMRXNdlW5ZlmM1msG0bvV4PhmHgfr\/j3VXaj8cjJpMJlsslFosFptMpxuMxDocDa87nMxRFQRiGH0diOBxiu922N8CyLKiq2t6+GQwGOJ1On+YQlNJqtUJRFLheryzSdZ1TIyh10zQRRVE31TRNuQn9fp8Fnudhv99zvfTRfD7Her3mJnYcicvlwrVSPQSNZrfbQdM0yLKMIAjYLomB\/kWSJO9RAMAXontOkoQvqEMAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  )\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>[1,  <img Width='14' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA4AAAAMCAYAAABSgIzaAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAFESURBVChTlZHPqoJAFMZ9BWnlgygErl25aFnrIDIQhBZB0qJo07qnEKQW7tq00RcQ3Bm4CF\/AAiv1u5xzncLLhcv9wTAzZ74z55\/UNA0EdK7rGs\/nE1VV8VnYhY7shCQe\/4vU7ng8HhxJRHy9XrxEZIpYliXbiI4jiUhAj7fbjYUitZ9I4oF+JeffiOMYjuNgs9kgz3O2vR3F7vs+RqMRXNdlW5ZlmM1msG0bvV4PhmHgfr\/j3VXaj8cjJpMJlsslFosFptMpxuMxDocDa87nMxRFQRiGH0diOBxiu922N8CyLKiq2t6+GQwGOJ1On+YQlNJqtUJRFLheryzSdZ1TIyh10zQRRVE31TRNuQn9fp8Fnudhv99zvfTRfD7Her3mJnYcicvlwrVSPQSNZrfbQdM0yLKMIAjYLomB\/kWSJO9RAMAXontOkoQvqEMAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  )\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">[<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">20, <\/span><img height=\"12\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA4AAAAMCAYAAABSgIzaAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAFESURBVChTlZHPqoJAFMZ9BWnlgygErl25aFnrIDIQhBZB0qJo07qnEKQW7tq00RcQ3Bm4CF\/AAiv1u5xzncLLhcv9wTAzZ74z55\/UNA0EdK7rGs\/nE1VV8VnYhY7shCQe\/4vU7ng8HhxJRHy9XrxEZIpYliXbiI4jiUhAj7fbjYUitZ9I4oF+JeffiOMYjuNgs9kgz3O2vR3F7vs+RqMRXNdlW5ZlmM1msG0bvV4PhmHgfr\/j3VXaj8cjJpMJlsslFosFptMpxuMxDocDa87nMxRFQRiGH0diOBxiu922N8CyLKiq2t6+GQwGOJ1On+YQlNJqtUJRFLheryzSdZ1TIyh10zQRRVE31TRNuQn9fp8Fnudhv99zvfTRfD7Her3mJnYcicvlwrVSPQSNZrfbQdM0yLKMIAjYLomB\/kWSJO9RAMAXontOkoQvqEMAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"14\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> )<\/span><\/p>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">[<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2, <\/span><img height=\"11\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA4AAAALCAYAAABPhbxiAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAE6SURBVChTlZG\/6oJQFMd9A9\/A13BwSXBJxxqa3VqCCBIaHFt8AKcg8S2kQQibgobAB5AWjRJsMqvv73dO3sLlB78PXM\/9nnv+eO6VXq8XBM\/nk9f9fsfj8eA9QTEijvxEJ\/E\/SK1FXdefLtSRNNmmadoI8P7Tkb+\/UBAtAQUITcUul0uniCSEmOd6vSJNU2RZxppYrVbQdR2apiGOY\/Z9ZqTE8\/kMx3GgqioGgwG22y2CIGDfbreDZVlQFAVFUXQvZzKZYLFY4HQ64Xg8wjRNGIaBqqr4vCxLLrrf778zEsPhEJ7ntQoYjUbo9XqtekO\/fDgcvh3JRlGE8XgM27bZuq6L6XSKMAx5FN\/3MZ\/PcbvduolEkiRYLpdYr9es8zzHbDZDv9+HLMvYbDbsl8S7\/AU9C90m3fYb4AdNwR4aSxF2lAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"14\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> )<\/span><\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>For a particular day of the year, it happens that the sum of the date and square root of the month gives the square of the month. What is the date?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>14<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> February\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>16<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> April\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>16<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> February\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>14<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> April\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Let M be the set of all even numbers from 1 to 25 and all the odd numbers between 26 and 200. If all the elements of M are multiplied, find the number of zeroes at the end of this product.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"22","CORRECT_ANSWER":"22","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">The figure given below consists of a circle with centre O. PQ is a chord of the circle and TQ is a tangent to the circle at Q. If <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Calibri;\"> <img height=\"12\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAwAAAAMCAYAAABWdVznAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAADoSURBVChThY89zkRQFIZnN0oaG1BYgcYibMMCFKJTUKolKgkK0ZBoRRRUOoXGzztzzoTMjE++J3nd+3Kei8e+7yBo\/c22bRzaH5zCfwzDwOsprOt6CZ1OWJYFwzB4fyscw7ZtQ9d1zPPM\/VYgHMeBqqqYpok78adAeJ4HSZLOb1+WhdeLQERRBEEQUNc1989nXwJRVRVkWUae59zpPp1+CsfPEU3TQFEUJEnC\/XP4IvR9D03TUBQF9zsedKFhURRhmibKskSWZZw0TTlxHKPrurdAbxjHEa7rIgxDBEFwie\/7aNv2NQ48ASY8D7PX3GOCAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"12\" \/> <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">POQ = <i>x<\/i>&deg; and <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Calibri;\"> <img height=\"12\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAwAAAAMCAYAAABWdVznAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAADoSURBVChThZAxDkRQEIb3PDo9FTdQuIMruAInoKKTqCTUSCRakYgOBaVagn8zs3myspH9kv\/N+1\/mn0ne6zxPEFSfdBwH9xBX4B9N03C9Avu+\/0hMdhwHlmXx\/TEgml3XhWma2LaN\/WOA8DwPuq5jXVf2xBWgiUJEFEVQFAXzPLMXQ24B8ViWJWRZRtu27L+33gJE13VQVRVVVbEXW38CRN\/30DQNeZ6zF81CxBUYxxGGYaCua\/ZPvOiYpgmSJMG2bRRFgSzLWGmack2SBMMwfAK0YVkW+L6POI4RhiGCIGCJO30vDQWAN8U9DhgekhNTAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"12\" \/> <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">PQT = <img height=\"27\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABsAAAAbCAYAAACN1PRVAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAALISURBVEhLrZZfSFpRHMetfKzQZ6GHVNpTjbLBZjmkp03KNx00hEzQCNbqIavJpsWyt\/VWsT\/Zy1wPbqNZaGuDJsryoViNxsJBDQfTesiiJoV+d+\/pdCt0NLz3Awfv9\/c79349nt\/5XUU4x8+tLdh7e9HZ2Qm3ewT7+\/s0Iwyc2c7ONpQKBaqqrsBms6GiogK3butoVhg4s6kpD5RKJRLJJNErK8sQiURYXPxEtBBc+BlPSTKGQ0ODkMlkiMd\/0Sh\/csxmZ\/2QSCRkVf39AzQqDDlm8Xgc0WgUo6NPiOH4xATN8Iczy2azOD4+puoEpVyO6zfUVPGHM3MPP0ZlpRxHR0dEs5\/l5WUwGu8QLQScWSQSQUlxMaqra9DT0wM5syqJRIq1ta90RmFsbyeZil5EJpO5uGcry8vMSoxQq9VoM5vxfWODZgqDXUBjQwOsVitaW+\/mFoiQ6PV6vH7zllyPuN38zVZXv2Bubo5cp9N\/mOYwhc3NLaIfDAygvd3CzFmF0WDkb+b3+1FWWoqHj5xwOZ1obm5GOBwmuXQ6DYfDAZPJhJdeL0SpVAqxWOy\/x8HBAXnQeUbcw+RMhkIhGsmPaGZmBh0dHaT5XjbYeYFAgN56xscPCygpESOV2qOR\/AhSIP19fRCLxZh\/v4DDw0NS5vko2IztOF5mH+x2O3w+H25qNKirU8Hj8eR0olMKN2O+vdncBqfLRfR8MAiLxYLd3V2i83HBLJH4ja6ue+RQs1X1anqaZoSBM2P\/AigUckilUtzv7oZWqyUV9vTZczqDP5zZO6Yq2Yevr3+jEaBepUKlXEEVf85WtrfHnKMfVJ1wrV6FhkYNVfz5Z4GMj42RlX5eWqIR\/uQ1G3Q5UVRUhCBTYUKSY2Y0GMh7LByO0IhwcGbsm1nf0oKamquXtp1C4cwmJ1+QPaqtrYVOp0NTUxMZNqYfCgPwFwbfaLi7MTSJAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"27\" \/> , what is the value of <i>x<\/i>? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhmAC7APcAAP\/\/\/\/\/bkDoAAAAAADqQ29fX17+\/v39\/f1hYWEBAQFBQULe3t8\/PzzoAZrb\/\/\/\/\/tmYAOpDb\/4+PjzAwMCgoKKenp6+vr0hISCAgIIeHh8fHx\/\/\/25A6AGa2\/+fn55eXlxgYGHBwcN\/f33h4eDg4OBAQEDoAOmhoaO\/v75+fn\/f392BgYAgICBkZGW9vb2VlZQBmtmaQ29uQZpA6Ov+2ZgAAOpDb22YAADo6ANuQOgA6kNv\/\/5qamkdHR7ZmAFRUVFpaWi4uLv+2kDo6kAAAZra2Zg4ODmYAZgsLCwYGBmlpaRERETw8PCwsLB8fHwQEBHR0dB4eHg8PD0NDQ3d3d5WVlQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAmAC7AAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KtKjRozIDCBjAdAABjwUMHDiAIIHVq1YVTF3AAGnGAA0cCHwAIQLGAhIUTBhAIcHUCgbiyo1rYeqFtRguZNDgdSJYsQA2cOhA0cMHBCAohLDQdaKIBSNIlFAgQURfh38FBjBhNmIFBSBOVPDAEYWFEBgSpFBxWaHSpgMIPyxwAgQCCyQNrACxgi\/KFSkzR2SggMIH0idRpCCRwIBJFSyCh4VIfALulgasOh9ZgIJ0wAw9rP+wLjN7ggIis39v+IFCCpsGJoxg\/TEFcJsFSJxAgVNFhgkLfDSVTRlQ4JtOBVywAn0brfDeTCgoMAJQy1m20QUBysQAeUFteF1GFKAXUwUtuMCfUBEeoBELDLokAQIvYIDBAScGdcB9FqFQQkwHhACACgkscMCMNf6UAgItSrQhTCGoKJAHE3iAwpA0BvVZkhAtcMFLK0hQkAYJsDYlkUAtoACWDn1wgksheGmQmgONWaVPZqLJ0AgZtJTBhAg5SJCcyPFk30R+rjRoQkAeKNCYIQSq04ARNbdSnQuJQIKjAqkgAQaN8lToQxhYiJIIFNhZkAEXoKkpp5jWlChEA6j\/9KpDEviI0Kqd4iTCBEUq5AEIKrUZEQIVKIRrqzJZoIBDGpCQkrISqUBCY4hummtNwjIE7UkeUNCrQ7t+a9CqK4gqk7TUJlQrSsRWpF5DKqSAQbk0NctQtiXZa9GeEMlLr0ztKhRwSROkS5ECHzrkr7kteYCBqQCQoKhI62KkwgQi9jsvwytVjBAIyHqkAgYhSxTuRAu7NHLJsZbkcUZaVuRvxiq9TJAIGJS0ckeQUpQCBQoY\/BzJB707ks0aIXyRBRMEXbOtBVWAQEkgf4QCCTRTxLTTJ6kAwrf8jrTtR\/mJK9HWQoeE70AnfEAShiKNjRHaJXVnkNIi\/UoSnhzR\/z2SxAUVPFLYI8Hdd9PbgQQnQSWYvZHgJKEwAcdzaweSwwxCx513JhUwAcTuWu6R4QDYLVLPJcndkXmJa3QoAEaDJClKa3vE+kY4D\/Q6SI2rNHtIt2fUOwCoe7SkSpJTLpFgA8BQtOgW4f3pR0ibxAAJoDcUQAwAyNCZQdlxSFHFpH+Et6E4PrTBDGbRUIMNHDS\/UHUJUzeBQCGKlH9LtTdEAwwPuIFsHkK\/aEUHACwKieZUdoHWNWR9OHjKRAoIkRDpSCSmc4kHSKC8hORABzuwCAUbgqHjgUR1LAETDxRwlQM4kCBKqcH3KjJChbQpZiEh3Es+0IMFyOU\/GHATQd0C2IEcSBAj1XlQQtS0OJC0bSZPJIgGJoAkgtzgKWSZ4UUYsAIMKNEgWuLbQHLQlAFaZGAwmVWcLkACx3VEBF384kCa9SkfgBAARMTI72ICpVadoFQngaMXC4Kz2QkHADS4o0X2GBMwYWkFfApkHAeCs1AJ5H9DLMtF9kcTpDmsgyER5Hug0zIA5MB5A1mfFiViSZusIANzicsPgBDLWtoyLhgR5QCAdUlUjkWTFqmaTVSwAqxYhQRBMKYyl2kV2DjzmdCEprM0Mx0hRCAAQwihRVrZmpEMYFljBGEAY\/+DEW6yhIxMMWNOBgA1gaCTCEVwykUYmZIPhjCAR9SVEYQouxee5AFHAM8hbyICJBRLJOdTSSK1GZjB6IQBSJiYR6aXEkwSxAfqrIkBklAyjRQPJRYViGAySpMUlDIkUmsJQAU6nZwoYQkkMeFKckAEseBzJ0xoQuR25BIalJEnTugB1TraTYw8AQolKV9ROVKAEriNJB9dakZSEIX6gSR2UtXICqKQNpGVIHtZhQgGjOBGjkAurBhBgRQOWJL+oXUiFpgC50qC1bcSigoJQIkw7ToRr1UhfXvLE18nIrWohkSmg30IwihKEk4mtiEoAIEKlApVJz2WPWtybEkwd9n\/hggugSlxa2cJAq0LqoSzo0WI4BB7EtGOdls4PO3DUmsQyDUxWPyk7djEuBIUUICodlUBBUTFWJTsbrSoo2dKztpZ1ArEnCthbWITCoCTtsSwbz2u3mKiXLR6Lkn6gkm3ytpNdBkEhS1Bb1bdWr2W8BatKT2Ia1lS3G6iyk5ojIkKFJAhqZYtIYBz1bSkukFQ7pUmUOqqUTyQAAULxLo0QUECJGoUSzkYALnLiYT7e5QCJACUAqmrq6g7lOuBWCDx1cl+2ymUD7TRITrUiQQuhSIEnACsAoliTzRAAQ7zJD8HVaxVdYKCC+yHJ\/7BmESY65P2BPkmU5zPRIYXFA8g6eACWYsJClaANYoskCgLmMC1XjImOUYkg0Q5lkvkRN6FiFgoqzpBlkkighGQCSPHNYoK2mOcNl8kXiTAQAb83BDsFoU2JSAWcCVimhWUoDcTNfNlpJaYE1iA0AdRAWQmMJnVgISyRS3ABxRQghIk4AQuNEDIUBCXDIQgARhggV4uDKI5Z5XVHziAVUAQTVMnYAQSMMCJOQJa2tbEtMauiXST\/ZLYMlsmt302TN4rbS5Jutor6S62UwLdba8Ewt5OyXbDncJpknsl6j03Sdqr7pHMt90gyS+8SRLgeZvkwPb2Zr5NkuF9j+TNWv7mSIoDDpIYE7wjOj64R0iscI0wueEOxzTEJ07xilv84vGDjSIv7peWcrwiA\/24REIucoiQvOSY8TjKTa7ylaccPC5\/ecxnTvOa2\/zmOM+5znfO8577\/CYBAQA7\" style=\"width: 152px; height: 187px;\" \/><\/font><\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>144\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>135\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>120\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>90\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>Chakradhar and Dhruva have two spools of 'manja' (a specially prepared thread) to fly their kites. Each of the manjas has tiny knots at regular intervals, which helps in keeping track of the length of the manja that is used. Each of the persons has the same length of manja. While Chakradhar's manja has knots at intervals of 10 feet, Dhruva's manja has knots at intervals of 12 feet. Also, Dhruva\u2019s manja has exactly 10 knots less than that of Chakradhar. If each of the manjas starts and ends with a knot, find the length (in feet) of the manja with either of them.  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"600","CORRECT_ANSWER":"600","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A television channel has eight programs \u2212 A through H \u2212 which are available for three prime-time slots on a Sunday evening. In how many different ways can the programmes be shown, if program A can come only after program B?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"228","CORRECT_ANSWER":"228","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The whole numbers from 0 to 84 (both inclusive) are written, from left to right, on a thin, long metal sheet, in the ascending order, all along its length, such that the gap between any two consecutive digits is the same. If the sheet is now cut into four equal pieces along its length, using three cuts, what is the sum of the two digits on either side of the rightmost cut?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">When the curve <em>y <\/em>= log<sub>0<\/sub><sub>.<\/sub><sub>1<\/sub> <em>x<\/em> and <em>y<\/em> = 16 &minus; <em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup> are drawn in the <em>x<\/em> &minus; <em>y<\/em> plane, how many times do they intersect for value <em>x<\/em> &ge; 0? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"2","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A tank is fitted with two taps A and B. The tank can be filled by opening A for two hours and B for nine hours or alternately by opening A for three hours and B for six hours. If the tank has to be filled using only A, how many hours will it take?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"5","CORRECT_ANSWER":"5","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Three beggars are about to eat their meal. One of them has 5 rotis, the second has 3 rotis, the third has no food but has 12 rupees with him. They share their food equally and the third beggar gives the other two Rs.12 for his share of rotis. How much did the second beggar get from the third beggar?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.1.50\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.4.80\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A sphere of radius R is melted to form n identical spheres of radius r. If both R and r are integers, then which of the following is necessarily true?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>n is a perfect square\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>n is a perfect cube\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>n is an odd power of 3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='15' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA8AAAAMCAYAAAC9QufkAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAFDSURBVChTfZBBywFRFIZZyZaaP2CjyBI7Kz\/ATinbISVZUlNTfoamSSyUhWwtjJJSNrZ208iChZXVDM\/Xvd\/t+1Iznjrd877dt3M6Mb6w2+3odDqR9TXc6\/WYz+dsNpvQigx7nkej0VAqnMjwbDZjNBopFU5kWKy83+8JgoDX66XcT0LDz+eTZrOJ7\/s8Hg\/q9TrtdpvVakWtVqPVasl\/sfP5zGAwYDgcSkOwXq\/p9\/tKwXg8Jh6P4zgOruuSTCY5nU7Ejscj0+mURCLB5XKRnw3DYLFYyF5gWRalUkkpyOfzTCaT\/7XL5TK6rsterHy\/32UvEJMrlYpSkM1mpfcX3m63pNNp+Xa7XeX+IiYXi0WlIJPJYNv258Gq1SqaprFcLpWDvLS4Ry6X43q9crvdKBQKmKb5GT4cDqRSKd7vt3K+AT9ovF4662VpVgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  is a perfect cube\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>In the year 2002, a person takes up a job for a certain salary. In the following year, his salary increases by 20% percent. In the third year, his salary increases by an amount equal to twice the increase in the year before. In the fourth year, the amount of increase in his salary is thrice that in the preceding year. If the salary of the person in the third year is Rs.16,000, then what is the difference (in Rs.) between the salary increase in the fourth year and the second year?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"10000","CORRECT_ANSWER":"10000","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If <em>x<\/em> is a positive integer, which of the following cannot be the value of (<em>x<\/em> + 3) (<em>x<\/em> + 5) (<em>x<\/em> + 7) (<em>x<\/em> + 9)? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3465\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5760\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7560\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>13440\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the time taken by the train to cross the platform?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>I. The length of the platform is 200 m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>II. The train takes 40 seconds to cross a bridge of length 400 m.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The question can be answered by using only one of the statements. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The question can be answered by using either statement alone. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The question can be answered by using both the statements together, but cannot be answered by using either statement alone. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The question cannot be answered even when both the statements are used together. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A train starting from Old Delhi railway station to Chandigarh railway station encounters 38 intermediate railway stations along its route. In how many ways can the train stop at exactly three intermediate stations such that no two of them are consecutive?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6545\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5984\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7140\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8436\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If six straight lines and five circles intersect each other, then the maximum possible number of distinct points of intersection is\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"95","CORRECT_ANSWER":"95","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If, when 950 and 1170 are divided by a natural number <i>d<\/i>, the remainders obtained are 18 and 5 respectively, then <i>d<\/i> is at most\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"233","CORRECT_ANSWER":"233","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Two circles having equal radii touch each other externally. If the distance between the centres of the two circles is 18 cm, then the length of the direct common tangent that can be drawn to the two circles is \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9 cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>18 cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>29 cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='24' Height= '14' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABgAAAAOCAYAAAA1+Nx+AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAKSSURBVDhPpZNPSJpxGMdtrEvz0J8FaULQP3PeokM7rXaQRXNQGzRKg6Axl8vZ0GLbySA71K7t0A4LtducghCt1oJF0DKkJb67JB3SKRSVoc388937e3qXG9XJD\/x4v8\/z\/Hi\/z\/t73p8IeXJwcACz2Qyj0XhhmUwm5G2wvLyM4eFh7OzsXLryNrBarXC5XEJ0kbwN9Ho9\/H6\/EF3k3GBjw4uFhUUhOmNlZQWjo6P4MDOD38mkkM1xcnKCvr4+ejK+r63BYrFgauodzYZBBr\/CYYjFYmg0Wkoy3k9PQyQSQaVSobS0FK2td5FMngrVMziOw8DAAOm3k5MoKCiAWq2GQqFATW0tjo+PIZqdnYW8vh7FxcUwGF7QZkalRAKttpe0f2uLzNa9GxT\/xel0Ynx8nHSlVIpXr9+QTp2e4hpvZrM7ILLZbFhdXYWmp\/v8hYzB53o0NjZifd0L69gYZDIZIpGIUD1jku\/a4XCQDoVCSKVSpLPZDBl8dH7KzeDRw87\/DH5sbqKw8DqkfGese5PJTPlsNktPBvvXvV6vEOXo4Zutrasjw0sN4vE4pPwR9fc\/QSwWw9elJZSUlGDQYIBcLofdbqd9bMCsfg5v3qvVoqJCwn9RmFKXGnBcgLrmuJ8UM5S3FLjT0oL29nYolUpEo1HodDqhCqTTabS13UNz820cHh4K2X8MHqjvo6vrMWn2BTfLytDdo8H+\/j4+z8+T4eKXJQS3t0mPjIxgYmKC9jM6OzpQVHQDPp8PwWAQgUAAR0dHOYNnuqcYGnopROwOfENNdTUNt7y8nD\/vIaECNDU1kcnc3BzFod1dVFVVoaGhgX7ROv782fJ4PDmDq9jb20Mmkxssw+12071JJBJC5iqAP3gGRmZ10AKKAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhPwGgAHAAACwAAAAAPwGgAIcAAAAAADMAAGYAAJkAAMwAAP8AKwAAKzMAK2YAK5kAK8wAK\/8AVQAAVTMAVWYAVZkAVcwAVf8AgAAAgDMAgGYAgJkAgMwAgP8AqgAAqjMAqmYAqpkAqswAqv8A1QAA1TMA1WYA1ZkA1cwA1f8A\/wAA\/zMA\/2YA\/5kA\/8wA\/\/8zAAAzADMzAGYzAJkzAMwzAP8zKwAzKzMzK2YzK5kzK8wzK\/8zVQAzVTMzVWYzVZkzVcwzVf8zgAAzgDMzgGYzgJkzgMwzgP8zqgAzqjMzqmYzqpkzqswzqv8z1QAz1TMz1WYz1Zkz1cwz1f8z\/wAz\/zMz\/2Yz\/5kz\/8wz\/\/9mAABmADNmAGZmAJlmAMxmAP9mKwBmKzNmK2ZmK5lmK8xmK\/9mVQBmVTNmVWZmVZlmVcxmVf9mgABmgDNmgGZmgJlmgMxmgP9mqgBmqjNmqmZmqplmqsxmqv9m1QBm1TNm1WZm1Zlm1cxm1f9m\/wBm\/zNm\/2Zm\/5lm\/8xm\/\/+ZAACZADOZAGaZAJmZAMyZAP+ZKwCZKzOZK2aZK5mZK8yZK\/+ZVQCZVTOZVWaZVZmZVcyZVf+ZgACZgDOZgGaZgJmZgMyZgP+ZqgCZqjOZqmaZqpmZqsyZqv+Z1QCZ1TOZ1WaZ1ZmZ1cyZ1f+Z\/wCZ\/zOZ\/2aZ\/5mZ\/8yZ\/\/\/MAADMADPMAGbMAJnMAMzMAP\/MKwDMKzPMK2bMK5nMK8zMK\/\/MVQDMVTPMVWbMVZnMVczMVf\/MgADMgDPMgGbMgJnMgMzMgP\/MqgDMqjPMqmbMqpnMqszMqv\/M1QDM1TPM1WbM1ZnM1czM1f\/M\/wDM\/zPM\/2bM\/5nM\/8zM\/\/\/\/AAD\/ADP\/AGb\/AJn\/AMz\/AP\/\/KwD\/KzP\/K2b\/K5n\/K8z\/K\/\/\/VQD\/VTP\/VWb\/VZn\/Vcz\/Vf\/\/gAD\/gDP\/gGb\/gJn\/gMz\/gP\/\/qgD\/qjP\/qmb\/qpn\/qsz\/qv\/\/1QD\/1TP\/1Wb\/1Zn\/1cz\/1f\/\/\/wD\/\/zP\/\/2b\/\/5n\/\/8z\/\/\/8AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAI\/wD3CRxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KtKjRo0iTKl2qMRiApxAEzmMRTaS+LlUJ6it0quTWrkzDFi2XoKo+QkZK7qIgpkoorVi9xhVLF6i+KmD3zdOhl6qiOALZRc1HBYCAqvNkgHkKuCAtqAXZHY78gBCAqA8fXzaoz0pWguwqb65LWie7sgannpKHWRdgtPtOR8unArA81AODRdW36K3AfDOezfi8L1iAU\/ncDmT3tHljgbr38fY9MJ+VvLmPJ6deuvvM0AL1Ff8+LI+q9WidV1OV7nYq4vUDlYUvxB0hrcZ\/HcqXTn9586dAEHSfQPl5Z2BMoX2mmnv7\/AXePCo0F0AoqvWV11nNCYDdQfoY0pU+BS6E4VMaFtQZcdJ5KF2IB7a40okDuVchOxYockdfxJX33mcJxoZbQleZpVxg\/wHwXI+yFWTdhkGyV5+LUJq0y2RnHcageFTCJuN6Oi5XFogPMMTOhPvQgpmYXypy5kJjvmVmlHCmxBxk+3RZ5pniAUBmhRWGZxkAYljAUDBvFCaoQyOKUYFDwcBhaJyQRirppJRWaumlmGaq6aacdurpp6AOtdWTH40a6qly\/vecknONlE+rqMbhepFmawpEC25nhWlQaIqM5lCvvopZgWW6ympsRNGZmluxA7lmkHGhbOefqgQl219D0N5F6rHcHrTfdAN1mBU7jc0znGP43djQt4uoy9CADbrb7byc\/WnYhXHRgkAkuxlCXIcfErIqkPZOtg9hRRYLsHQC0+swZVUl+VtcTgGQlj5c\/BvXXXnN6dxyD0T8o0JNavvwyT6ipwiz4CpDrnzAEdfmnQ7JBmbNZL6J8sOJHjrQLrWWOTChhQVN8FOBMlooAIdKu\/PTzeJKhdEvCSMv1Dt7bKRN+jSC9ddghy322GSX\/222RvSgON+2ECl79tsDpc1huxltwTbcYZ81cHiwUvSq2nifrBmzgaFhdGjEQjR4YMMCQHjg9ALN34aZLPnscSYTSe3Pu3G1zy4TZg65w9AMZDdB82xSXIDoErg3QqULdLqzDb4+uqwjGkZcL4jNYKKKINpuYsHoZbyi8LefmqTEB2syn7wlDxlbkUeiZvPG0id\/bIJn+bxPLx17P2ZXOosZMohRjd8g1dqfmqjChf1ncHFLP340oGE2WpiuTrfvP0W82ND\/BsiQrgGOgAhMoAIXyMAGOvCBEIygBCdIwQpa8IIYzGDZdoG8hUAIAKwryAdDSBEOalAnbqsIYTqoEP9ehAJgW3GXCxfWkBgSZIUnbAmwMoSdv2HEFphgoYic1yStOA9RsAKiEHN4EWCxzDNSgQNlemW\/hAArKvOAAzuudrDrHMSJa4uNA6gYRiV5MTJj3EwWt8hEkQRDV9dynUB4V5BsSU9rW8tN506xCxIxCYp11FVv7qIuO76wClyUDiCrNaHk8NGPbQQJu+QVs3yQwSDwYpFCvnUtcoGmSCTk5B00c5gC0eIOwCqR5ppDwkw2xpOR9Eju5je5dtRnYcGrYcEEqJVF+ilD\/\/IXw5AHI60AT5Ox7MjyRhabBzQCRdGjDh6PFLJmHvA3Z\/SSyP41BiHxsjrZ5JuQ7pbMi3BEb2WcocLeZlY+Nn2JEOxTyG1UVquZqWki7IxnOS\/Ss4MMQ21EY9pDErUoiRC0jo4KFkQC6r19OvShEI2oRCdK0Ypa9KL\/GM2oRjfKUQUCi5kdjVV0ykTCkHJLEWkxqbE0wxiVyipJonNpqHpEC1rKVFThAlIhEikRzeCABd+86U6UsR+iCsSoBvGhUA8ExoGUTgxoEAgAnEeMGACOV45banfeKJA4HhUAAllBJvaBhhggxJDT+phWjcLJPhSEGGDdhwGIsQ8xhME++FniWoMySxRBw6z7EGtdo8qZY+qVIEVK7FP26pJlZqUeAxHDWGPwTzRAljPYkyb1GDuUed7sIMTIBKCIsZ9d5UyfnBVKotgHjRW8QSEMTS2kADDWkwhGtkG5AV1PEozD4hZKW8EEnX5rKfEMRp3EtZTEdpHS5E6qtwOhRkVznQspvYUne9SFk3Fthdrsdic0Fauid8dL3vKa97zoTa9618ve9mIQYSWFCHzTqw8t+FZJ8QMAAgBnQ4twsIgFPJ1A\/tv\/t\/Fat4R5\/ByZWHXNh9BGrwA+WG04+8GtJUYLLT1YYRAAhg42NUbw0SZlEveQD++DEcSxnEHWIRpm2SKoJrVuMMoijwnbjBBHmB7yJJfC\/DglAJmYATQaRhDQnUJ00yxymEb1X0Zgp5h1xJxb\/ivM1LonH+vBcjQqlMuElHan4IzGLr40tX3ooqS0QyZCvnzkwoQQjyWF133yNN21pvIUfAKqufwkvL56CRp4sdWNWIQxsxCCp8PjIZB8GR7gdRi34knLlnaED6AK5NEIcexyHJCM9ejDblCWTmbTmuGU+UghKobLOHHLoJpumUvrgQ1zhHdOZpnLZLR4wJDrrL57\/zaEe4QoaETU187UagYO1ylPV7i8YUxz6E9iWJMj5\/SGCMU3oOKtF9K6+6yEPq5\/7mXImNVW7HAnhRYLlg4Vsm3uolRYTzBut7znTe962\/ve+M63vvfN7377+98AD7jAB07wghv84AhPuMIXznCcvBsACUCGpUlm34Eou08ZUTY\/MUzCGj8AQmTaRXwZbCIB1+lcBpGbQUSukU9TRx7DQdjeVF4QllfE5RY\/lyLSfZDY7eOaNl8Iwp4CUpwLBOYNPgiDInJgHNkpI0uvSNShE6CYnbzBu3BAWygJq6CHi8gEQfqvN0fy3ASo6Xw2iNgVskNITow4Ng9GfPWhjGUcdf8\/xKiHz4+OcoX08TnQKjvVI4JxHF04wwjjcGMQJoBPsGAxeWQ8dgr0oAhZWM+WVrbkC1LjeyGM57sIgl5kUJVTDsTEsbEp4rKqyA2xAwePCxHqG4QrQjxu9bpKz1mu9vrYPwf154kiaFocHih6fR92h6pU6TqMG5T29L9\/CuGmbmqQkTjUDJn6gmz8zgDNGsSz4T56COH9\/YLMdTIui3u6NJUhl\/8z4gHMOtQ\/8YGso+rDSQ904Egd4Dij78UhZb4BLwORCfoXLoDEVfvgVQpIEJpkHEc2JANScQRhgOFUTAroVbUzR8QBgZmTH8zlLXElWGJwA5yRgPzngIDxY0F9NmSr4oFDomYJ0Xkk8mrR0CVaxmWHBmJ4lmVUwWXScyLBB34XZ2lT4XirxnfjNHX1BRh7Zi5Z0VbvkleDZ3GqE4I5F4Xz4VaNNi6LB4CuRHVoJw9XOF1rJ4U3FHOXJCBUuDrVRxBwJRBzRVZcoHYoh4ZdJGZkFibSxYZy5Ib\/DzF1OpJnyIFyYLcly6Znlqcn3AEJcXBbBOJHk9YXz7CI6QZTXIFxyoIPwxEPCfBLNSgihlWFc7RsfTdPDANM4ZIv+9Iv8DeKn3MEXVaKenGKqOFnWsEVtmRMH1Ig5ZBSVkcQfxVWY6V8kXGLxPNnQ+IsIYJLBXJ\/EFF4C7Ie6+dpOygVVNElgxhikQEBzhJphveDsNZpgDMPObCE3LgPDfOE54IkIGUio\/Y5ovcblVBGtRgY1cQ8PlQxF6Mi4uQkAxYgYJcP9cgf1LFn1vSGIPNMqgaQ8qiQkTVWMOA8YqB0OYCP2wQyEmcWXAFl0TRgORaI3DiJGidrCVaE73Fk\/1pSfxpWIq1mJUCVHDdSU6awknmBQzN2gyz5OWlRSVBkM+jEJqcVXc9BR0d3JpYDlCzTHy4TBzDTd\/nULHEwi0ZZJ0jpRUrJIcgFGkMpEM6Chf6kCYCSCc8HTl2RldUxAyajCAngflzpJmdCgA2hfeKYiFWReM6mjgLwDEboaYXBc7biM8CCbD1YFRWDbOjxl\/XxQZNBfcEgemKXH6s1KEuDJ4A0dKpoK4AxmdUSNHIZUJapkouXX6GomakIKFTzT3VUmQjYFdCYEK1VW3h1mtF2Q25BbRFSZ7FVfMiBXZlSDvgnFeeoEWCZfcO5ELeSFeLBblWYlwphjkknEXIXkE4LQVvPeZwJkZOYpE\/TGSoQAgE1FnJ1RhFQCBHFmRBaI0R7JnMPcZ4XgZDoFm+6tRDHdxDoRh3b9Zy+03AkQRsSQk78GaACOqAEWqAaERAAOw==\" style=\"width: 319px; height: 160px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>a<\/i><sup>3<\/sup> + <i>b<\/i><sup>3<\/sup>\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>a<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> \u2212 <i>b<\/i><sup>2<\/sup>\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>a<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + <i>b<\/i><sup>2<\/sup>\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>a<\/i><sup>3<\/sup> \u2212 <i>b<\/i><sup>3<\/sup><sup>\r\n<\/sup><\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There are three measuring jars J<sub>1<\/sub>, J<sub>2<\/sub> and J<sub>3<\/sub>. First J<sub>3<\/sub> is filled with water and then emptied into an empty vessel A. Then J<sub>2<\/sub> and J<sub>3<\/sub> are both filled with milk and emptied into another empty vessel B. Finally J<sub>1<\/sub> is filled with milk drawn from B. If the capacity (in litres) of J<sub>1<\/sub> is at least 3 and at most 8, that of J<sub>2<\/sub> is at least 6 and at most 12, and that of J<sub>3<\/sub> is at least 7 and at most 14, then the volume of water in A as a percentage of the volume of milk in B is at most\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>116.67%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>140%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>132.8%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>107.69%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the sum of the 10<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup>, 20<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup>, 30<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> terms of an arithmetic progression is equal to the 58<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> term, what is the ratio of the sum of the 10<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup>, 20<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> and 30<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> terms to the sum of the 5<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup>, 10<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> and 15<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> terms?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20 : 9\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>19 : 9\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhegEwAPcAAP\/\/\/\/\/\/25CQtraQkNv\/\/7ZmOpDb\/\/\/bkDpmtv+2Zma2\/\/\/\/tmYAAAAAADqQ25A6Zrb\/\/2Y6kNuQOjo6kJA6OgBmtgAAZrZmAAAAOpBmkAA6kDqQvJA6AAA6OjoAOma229v\/29uQZpCQZjoAAGYAOjoAZmYAZrb\/tjo6ZmY6AAA6ZrbbkGZmAABmZtvbkDo6AGaQkJC2kJBmAGa2ttv\/tgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAegEwAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KdGAAAQoHEKh4NOnSolCjSnVZwIDCAwgqVr2adarXr2A7JlDAcOxEswvRhl3Ltm3BBQwaOAAQ4AEEhgsiPFUIVy5du3j1uh1M2KuEuQIPTNibMAAFqwsPD1TMGKFjyIUza+7ZtwFZAAkqEExg4e4FDJgvfA6QoXLnz6EJSgYA9zMA1Ztz675JeaAE0QNr\/y54ATHrygB6CxzuGzHugcV3S5\/ucvZyxNAbAJdtvLVB6wDAS\/8gCz48duoN0qtXT729xsuyty\/XgFzCBg7rtRt9HF+2AuXNuQdAAwIWyBGAoMknQQceYAbdat4RhGBsvn3AH3G2TUeggRxiVJ5yEmgAAgfn0XXhcQV9uNhAIYhQookO\/nTACOllOBGBCaSHWoc8OrQACTHWBQFc9IVXGkF5PYVicEAWJKRvRb4lWFC1gbZjRQ0c0CBoR\/a40gElQBAAfiVe0ECU5VGEYEZqJdTmQ2gtYMJdBr1p0Zg2monmXPAlt6JDCRSJp0UbCvRjjI2RCSadidq26KIbQcoUmcSd+ZR1ctLZ55oMPRqmkxf6iRxFaWKklEJNUTTAiFc6idRGg+7\/h1lvmQYoUZUUFTrfqAdJ2lCsyYXpK0bDSlRsn6JC12Wt10UE5glxtTpjA13iBl8CrdI2p5McfFYcs5F2hdBWaop7ELkJTetZciikUKOhcamQgqM0VvsZZTM6AO5DIfLaUKEzZstXtAY82u67tMU7L7zUrlACCwj31aVAz8WmLllgOnwXpBIzmli90DYgbb10PgdaC9uKmu++nQr7KXfBpRwarjF7TDHGK5oMWn42SjVovzOSFSgBY86VY4aYylyBlpCZnON6PRtpc0S6cjk1QpA+OoLQ9BW9s6PCbg1a1ySOvReFqv1MX8afLur10MExQJ4GLrxsq7Z0ynmC0kzf\/wyRpzabrJxjL5z3tHrnSfZcqZkBHiwEkAJ7m6N\/XgCD2M3ym+2Y+ck3YKFV09ZkQ1m7vLHpdHU7GeqOH1rzvp5q\/DjHoyf7Ywx2+53Yn4cxaznm5v2NuqwDwb2rQSwnCOKLDOXn\/PPQRy\/99M4rZCa1kLct7IrAIgs35+tm3pAEEztEYHoChe466dpnfzrk3KueGOthq5etahTell5pbL+vrsiY+R4FcOcx7xWJMrUCn20Yh7XhGSplyUrOCASGN4MoRgYLNBzPPoIuC5rLIB0sCFYGNhfHOQ5Y4KIVkPJnncMhLDFbutGGNkSajf2pZf5rX+TkNzsd5m40FcANXP9K6DLZOc6CK7pd7lK4IgmsBzWHYiHz0uXACFZQOFPs1QiiNLmU2KkgXwRN1EYzxsfdhn\/te1v4rFirEfqujJWCGtXO55v9Xa2BOXyfGsHmvsd5bVhwORKkLoDGEzSJkGIqm6+qFKK6eQxA+2pjVt4ovD4Wz3OqGaLoEIWQ9VWwIsUyiJlE8yS+TGmUf7ljcKZ0kOvNYE6lu0tf5GWb\/PltNpJJHkjYExFPxjKWCWsALY3CAQsY8VN9oeAFtuNKWIbJiQ14pSwJJkKSDcuWXaxZ8IKXKU9G6oYRsSUDG5Kj8iEvZZwClVWYlU6CIIsk6RxnR3gZkRBwcjrt\/E4WNSJTz4MEklH5ZMhpCJgukiWIeNhKzX8MSqFYRedBKElTQGWyJAP104qN+2GKsMMcgcxMbgSJjnU6ihsEPdRLKE2pBTUa0gy6kwKF22g2txk8ndFUpTiqRanb8LMeUoaqo8fjDrI6Gpo1XTSnSN1NKCdzQ1sGLEaqAVD+Ltgzmyb1qu1ZqkfloxwsvtQATv3TjLgokHdi9azS0epNn6RJTyYJPKX0pqFYida64jSMxRsjWrDpUTja9a8GOpVlXoWQAdCAAeakC2EBy9gejXBc90zMBwkSwsZa9rKYzaxmN8vZznr2s6ANrWhHS9rSmva0qE2talfL2ta69rWwja1pAwIAOw==\" style=\"width: 378px; height: 48px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='18' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAQCAYAAAAbBi9cAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHjSURBVDhPjZM\/SKpRGMa\/zRztLgU1lTdwdNawpD+4iA6KuriJKOgS2p2lQFzFzVGug4u3C6WDDkVuDi66COUfShAVNaVrPX3n9Wg0dLw\/OHCe932\/55z3nPNJWEEmk4HP51s5VhqZzWakUinkcrlvR6FQEBvVajUYjUauxAiNkskkPB4PV2KERn6\/H4lEgqs5rVYL4\/GYq0+ERiaTCeVymea5m2uo1WooFAqoVCpcXFxSfMG3Ru12GwaDAbPZDM1GA5IkQa\/fR6lUQiQSIZ3N\/uHVAiN27S6Xi+a1ahVutxuNZpM0Q7m2hvPzX1wJjEKhEKLRKFeflO7v4Zffzdb2NiqVCo8KjCwWC4rFIldzHh8esLuzQ23pdHp0u12ekY2YiMVickKHer1OwX6\/T+czHA5JL5hOpxiNRqjKrf5YX4fh4BBvb++Uk9LpNL0VtorD4aBgPp+H1WqlOWMymSwXWRA6O6NvXl4mpJetOZ1OSrAdxuNxhMNhngFu5KtnudvbOx4BDuQdb2xs4vX1H+mlEfsdWHEwGITX65WvNsszwGAwwN7eTyiVSlrg9OSEan\/L3Sz4ctg2m40KNBoNer0ej855fnpCIBCAVqvF0dExrq7+8sycL0adTodert1u55H\/BfgAogfIyqEHnmgAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='16' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABAAAAAgCAYAAAAbifjMAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJOSURBVEhL5ZU\/aFpBHMdfBxtMQaHtrIUqLuJULaQRgiJuzdLWodGqnTSIi6mTgZSUKuKq0dqtabtrIUWQWidxEVwcnFREBRGn1L\/fvrueKY88\/5Cp0A\/84H539z7v3u88j8MG\/CwUcHLylmVC1goajQaUSgUe6Q2sR8hKQTj8HlKpFHK5HAbDY9YrZKlgPp\/jtduNbPYbDr0ePFSp2YiQjWrgdjn\/e8GL589w9959lgnZSJBOf8DR0RuWCdlIsIp\/QEB+cZPJ5MbBpdNp7O3t3ShMJhO44XCIZrMpGq1WC91uF71eTzTI+NoakBd0Op1rQcSElYJSqQStViu6fLPZTFexUhCNRhGPxzGdTkWDsFLg8\/lQLpdZJs5Kgd1uR7\/fZ5k4SwWkwk6nk\/4zEc4SCVitVthsNhSLRdpHWCrI5XIIBoO07XzlAMdxCIVCcPFSjruFi4vvdGypgBQvlUphPB5Dp9PxJ\/IjGwGUCgW\/CxbaXioIBALI5\/Ms+0u9XodMJsPp6TuaLxU4HA60222W\/eHg4CXubG\/z98QDjPiVEa4E5G2Lbx4MBnQHyGFZQIpZqVRQKPyAWqXC0\/192kcF5DstFgstVK1WQ7Vahd\/vv3pwNpvR9oKvXz7TuWQVVEAmjEYjGI1GeDwe\/jLJIhaL0cmtVhMKvmifzs9pTojwNxYR0OPM+iiZTIZeYy6Xi24jgazOuLuL21tbSCaTiETC9GGv95COXyuiWq2GRCKhdVjw6\/ISx8ch6PV67Ow8QSJxxkZEBGTvNRoNy9YB\/AZGGQo5ldlG9wAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8 <img Width='18' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAQCAYAAAAbBi9cAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHjSURBVDhPjZM\/SKpRGMa\/zRztLgU1lTdwdNawpD+4iA6KuriJKOgS2p2lQFzFzVGug4u3C6WDDkVuDi66COUfShAVNaVrPX3n9Wg0dLw\/OHCe932\/55z3nPNJWEEmk4HP51s5VhqZzWakUinkcrlvR6FQEBvVajUYjUauxAiNkskkPB4PV2KERn6\/H4lEgqs5rVYL4\/GYq0+ERiaTCeVymea5m2uo1WooFAqoVCpcXFxSfMG3Ru12GwaDAbPZDM1GA5IkQa\/fR6lUQiQSIZ3N\/uHVAiN27S6Xi+a1ahVutxuNZpM0Q7m2hvPzX1wJjEKhEKLRKFeflO7v4Zffzdb2NiqVCo8KjCwWC4rFIldzHh8esLuzQ23pdHp0u12ekY2YiMVickKHer1OwX6\/T+czHA5JL5hOpxiNRqjKrf5YX4fh4BBvb++Uk9LpNL0VtorD4aBgPp+H1WqlOWMymSwXWRA6O6NvXl4mpJetOZ1OSrAdxuNxhMNhngFu5KtnudvbOx4BDuQdb2xs4vX1H+mlEfsdWHEwGITX65WvNsszwGAwwN7eTyiVSlrg9OSEan\/L3Sz4ctg2m40KNBoNer0ej855fnpCIBCAVqvF0dExrq7+8sycL0adTodert1u55H\/BfgAogfIyqEHnmgAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A point P is 3 units from the line 3<i>x<\/i> + 4<i>y<\/i> + <i>k<\/i> = 0 (L<sub>1<\/sub>) and 4 units from the line 4<i>x<\/i> - 3<i>y<\/i> + \u2113 = 0 (L<sub>2<\/sub>). The reflection of the point P on L<sub>1<\/sub> is P<sub>1<\/sub>; the reflection of P<sub>1<\/sub> on L<sub>2<\/sub> is P<sub>2<\/sub>; the reflection of P<sub>2<\/sub> on L<sub>1<\/sub> is P<sub>3<\/sub>; the reflection of P<sub>3<\/sub> on L<sub>2<\/sub> is P<sub>4<\/sub>. Find the area (in sq.units) of the figure formed by joining P<sub>1<\/sub>, P<sub>2<\/sub>, P<sub>3<\/sub> and P<sub>4<\/sub>.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"48","CORRECT_ANSWER":"48","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Ram and Shyam were trying to solve a quadratic equation. Ram copied the coefficient of <i>x<\/i> wrongly and obtained \u2212 4 and 24 as the roots of the equation. Shyam copied the constant term wrongly and obtained \u22129 and 13 as the roots of the equation. Find the roots of original equation?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>\u221212, \u22128\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>\u221212, 8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8, 12\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>\u22128, 12\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the last three digits in the binary representation of the number 76548926.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>010\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>100\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>011\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>110\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"}}